Okay sexy peeps, it's
time to make a
flippin' video. Now, below
this video you're watching
right now, what you're
going to find is
a list of instructions
that you can just
follow step by step
for this process. But
let's start this whole
thing off with the
golden rule for making
your demo video, and
it is this. The
enemy of success is
not failing, it's lack
of taking action. So
what I want you
to do when you're
producing this demo video
is anytime you catch
yourself going, but if
I say that, will
it wreck retention? What
if people don't like
this? Just say, YOLO,
who cares, and keep
going. Because nobody dies
if you post this
video and it's not
perfect. Okay, so now
you know our golden
rule, let's do a
quick overview of the
video creation system that
we're kind of going
to use for every
video we make. And
it looks like this.
It's beautiful, isn't it?
So the first thing
you always do is
you start by coming
up with a title,
and then you come
up with your thumbnail.
And if you ever
do a script first
and then try and
make a thumbnail and
title after, I'm going
to come to your
hands. And I am
going to stick this
so far up your
****** until ******, and
then I'm going to
pour it up there
until people mistake you
for a fountain. Sorry,
one sec, something wrong
with my camera. But
why is it so
important that you always
do your thumbnail and
title first? Well, all
jokes aside, if you
don't do it in
this order, you're about
80 % more likely
to make a video
that doesn't get traction,
because we have to
work out how to
make our idea clickable
before we make it.
And if we can't,
we don't waste time
making it. The click
is the start. The
click is the start
of the sales system.
So we can't do
it in any other
order. We then build
the intro, plan the
content, the script, and
everything else around what
might get us that
click. Now, the next
phase is going to
go into way more
details on packaging, but
the rest of the
system works like this.
So you plan the
title, plan the thumbnail,
then plan the content,
write it, produce it,
post it, measure it,
learn a lesson, and
then take what you
learn into another video.
That's it. So now
let's move on to
our demo video and
start with step one,
the title. So we're
going to go deep
on strategy and ideas,
and then we're going
to go into the
idea generation later. But
for our demo, I
just want you to
pick one of these
proven formats here.
I X and learned
Y, e .g. I
scaled 1 ,000 marketing
agencies and learned this.
Or X lessons about
Y that X, so
that could be 20
lessons about guitar solos
that turn beginners pro.
I wish I knew
this before I started
X. That could be
I wish I knew
this before I started
investing. X beginner lessons
every Y should know.
That could be 20
beginner lessons every tattoo
artist should know. Just
pick one of them.
Don't worry about it
too much. Now, if
you've got really strong
credibility and results, the
first option is fantastic.
And then the only
other thing you need
to do here is
try to keep your
title under 55 characters.
But don't get worried
if it's 56. This
is just practice. Then
step two, we're going
to make our thumbnail
for it. Again, whole
more advanced process on
this coming up. But
for this video, I
just want you to
try out my favorite
thumbnail strategy of all
time. It's called cognitive
dissonance. Now, this is
the first type of
image strategy I ever
think of for every
video I make because
it's so powerful getting
a click because it
basically challenges what your
viewers believe to be
true. Like these examples
you can see on
screen right now. I
mean, come on, you're
thinking, why shouldn't I
buy a house, right?
And these videos absolutely
slapped for views, which
is Shenzi for performed
well indeed. And all
you do is you
simply add text to
your image that says
stop doing X or
do this instead. Now,
the way I come
up with these, I
think to myself, what's
the thing most of
my clients do that's
totally wrong and they
never showed?
And then that text
usually becomes apparent. Anyway,
once you have that
text idea, which isn't
easy and it still
needs to work with
your title, I need
you to pick from
one of these two.
So if you are
an experienced channel, I
want you to reuse
an old image and
now add your text
on it. We don't
want you to whack
up a totally new
random thumbnail style or
even take new photos.
This is just about
speed. And if you
are a newer channel,
I want you to
take a fresh, just
very clear, simple photo
of yourself and add
text beside it using
whatever image software you
currently have. And just
make sure you keep
it simple. And then
I want you to
make a second version
of that same image,
but change the text
to a result like
this. So it could
be 10K subs in
30 days, could be
3X leads in 30
days, could be win
more games. And the
reason I want two
right now is because
we're going to use
YouTube's thumbnail split tester
when we post it
to see which one
performs best for you
as our first little
measurement test. So that's
it. Now don't forget
below the video there
are step by step
instructions to follow. Just
in case you're going,
I can't keep up.
All right, step three
is you get feedback
on your thumbnail. So
you do this by
going to the thumbnail
feedback bot in the
custom AI and just
putting your image in
and saying, give me
feedback on this image,
please. What it's going
to do is it's
going to check the
basics, the big design
mistakes that are really
common, and it's going
to flag things that
it might deem as
kind of needing improvement.
Now, keep in mind,
this isn't about perfection.
It's not about actioning
its advice right now.
So it's just really
about learning the process.
Now, if you like,
you can make the
changes that it says.
If not, just move
on. Don't overthink this
and get caught up
in doing a mountain
of work. We just
need to get this
bad boy posted. Now,
if you are a
member, you then submit
your demo for human
feedback in the packaging
feedback channel like this.
And what I want
you to do is
write, can I get
feedback on my demo
video, please? And then
put the title like
this and then put
the first thumbnail in,
hit enter. Put the
second thumbnail in, hit
enter. What I need
you to do is
post one image at
a time so they're
easy for us to
see from like a
bird's eye view. Otherwise,
it looks like this
and we can't. Now,
I do need to
state this is not
the ongoing feedback submission
process. Just this demo
one. The coming modules
are going to teach
you the more advanced
system. But all I
need you to do
is to make sure
you say this is
a demo video. So
the team and I
don't go giving you
black belt feedback tips.
They're going to totally
overwhelm you whilst you
are still a white
belt. All right. So
before we move on
to how to plan
this video and write
it up, now seems
like a pretty good
time to show you
why I chose this
style of video as
our demo video. And
it's called a listicle.
So firstly, a listicle
is one of the
most proven formats on
YouTube. They have worked
for a lot of
channels and in loads
of different niches since
the beginning of time.
And the cool thing
about them is they're
a little less complex
to make because they're
basically just a series
of unrelated points. So
there's no wrong or
right order to your
information technically. So for
example, a five mistakes
video, that's a listicle.
A seven lessons learned
from freelancing video, also
a listicle. Our demo
video listicle style is
really fast to make
too because this video
is built from your
own lived experience. So
you don't have to
do anything else other
than just spew out
what you already have
up here in your
head. It's also great
because you can then
easily turn this script
into an email, a
community post, or a
social media post. Which
means you're going to
get more return on
the time you put
into it. But most
importantly, it uses the
three foundational blocks of
great scripting. And these
are blocks we're then
going to add more
complexity to later on
so you can hit
black belt level. Alright,
so now let's move
on to step four.
We're going to start
planning this thing. And
all I want you
to do is block
off 30 to 60
minutes. I want you
to tell your family
if they disturb you
during this time, you're
going to barbecue the
dog. And then I
want you to write
20 very short lessons
you learned that relate
to this video. And
then I want you
to write a little
bit to your title.
But don't write more
than one very short
sentence for each one.
So you can see
my example on screen
right now. This is
when I did it.
And I'll link to
the actual final video
below as the full
thing might inspire you.
But you can see
I've got stuff like
your hard work will
pay off. Stick to
the plan. The people
you admire will eventually
find your videos. Practice
writing hooks every day.
And that's kind of
it. It's simple, right?
Now the first few
lessons, they're going to
feel tough for you
to come up with.
But once you get
them going, they're going
to start to flow
more. Now, if you
get into the flow
and writing them feels
easy and you hit
20, just keep writing
until it stops feeling
easy or until you
hit that final 60
minute mark. Because we
can then pick the
best ones from the
list and we can
always reuse the others
in another video, email
or post if this
one does end up
doing well. All right.
So pause the video
and just do that
route. 20 short lessons.
Again, don't overthink this.
Just get it done.
All right. Welcome back.
You didn't do it,
did you? You're thinking,
I'll watch the rest
of the video. First,
and then I'll come
back to that. Naughty.
Anyway, step five. Now
I want you to
do is remove any
lessons from that list
that are very similar
because we need each
one to feel unique.
And it's very likely
that some of yours
are pretty much the
same set in different
words. So to do
that, just copy your
list, throw it into
chat GPT and ask
it to remove any
that repeat or are
very similar. And then
I want you to
ask it to group
the random list into
categories. So this will
stop your video jumping
from lessons. That maybe
feel super unrelated each
time and group them
together in a way
that will be easier
for our viewers to
follow. Again, don't overthink
this. Just get the
video done. Now, if
you don't have AI
to do this for
you, because the one
in the course isn't
really designed for that,
just do it with
your real human brain.
Okay. So that moves
on to step six.
So what we need
to do now is
I want you to
think of a story
that taught you each
lesson. And I want
you to write it
as one sentence above
the lesson on your
doc. Now that's important.
It needs to be
above the lesson. Like
this, not below. You'll
see why in a
minute. Now, the story
could be about when
you learned the lesson
or when a client
of yours did. So
here's an example of
mine. So my story
is I had 2000
subs and people mocked
me for trying to
teach, but I stuck
with it. And years
later, some of those
people were in my
DMs asking for my
help. And then the
lesson is your hard
work will pay off.
Stick with it. Now,
before you go and
do this, I need
to show you how
to write a story
in just one sentence.
Because simplifying this and
keeping it simple is
not going to help
you. Keeping it brief
is very hard, but
this is the awesome
skill to build up
right now. So the
trick is to write
your story like this.
What I want you
to do is start
with the problem you
had that the lesson
solved. Then say one
action you took that
solved it. Then say
the outcome. So can
you see on my
example here, the red
is the problem, the
orange is the action,
and the green is
the outcome. It really
can be that basic.
If you want, pause
it and give it
a read. And whatever
you do, don't expect
this to be easy.
Simplifying is hard, but
it is the name
of the game on
YouTube. Okay, so step
seven, just make a
copy of that list.
And one of them
can become the email
you then send or
post to social media.
That's it. Congratulations. You've
already completed your first
bit of content. In
the end, I actually
went and taught each
lesson and I made
them into a tweet
and different community posts.
So you have potentially
just written 20 days
of content there too.
Now step eight. And
what we're going to
do is we are
going to write the
intro for your video
script. So the first
thing I want you
to do is watch
the intro I made
for this exact video
type, which performed really
well. And then I'm
going to help you
turn my intro into
your intro. I had
parasites from filming this.
You can see the
iron deficiency around my
eyes. Too much info.
Enjoy. Did you think
growing a YouTube channel
was going to be
easy? I did. And
I made over 300
YouTube videos and eventually
generated millions of views.
But my gosh, was
it such a grind.
And I really wish
I could have done
things smarter to speed
up results. So to
help make growing your
business's YouTube journey. 10
times easier. Here are
40 brutal truths about
growing a business's YouTube
channel. I wish I'd
known a lot sooner.
Okay. So to help
you do your first
intro really fast and
easy. I made that
intro into a template
that you can use
and it works like
this. I put it
on screen. Do you
think topic was going
to be easy? I
did. And then you
just want to insert
an credibility building thing.
So I said I
made 100 videos or
work with clients or
spent two years doing
something. And eventually I
and then insert the
result your viewers want.
So I said, grew
my channel. But it
was a grind. I
really wish I'd known
how to do it
smarter. So to help
you make whatever their
desired outcome is, put
that in 10 times
easier for you. Here
are the amount of
things you're going to
tell them. I wish
I'd known about whatever
the topic is that
would have saved me
a ton of time.
So all you have
to do is take
that template, which is
below the video and
just fill in the
gaps for your own
topic. And then present
it out loud before
you shoot it just
to make sure it
flows. Now, you're going
to need to use
some common sense here
today. OK, if you
hear it back and
you think to yourself,
hey, on a second,
this intro doesn't sound
right or it could
be confusing. Edit it.
This is just a
template. It's not something
God handed to me
one morning as the
ultimate holy template that
will fit every single
situation ever because that's
in the advanced modules.
All right. So now
it's time to take
a little task break
so that you can
rest your weary typing
fingers because you need
to understand why the
way we're making this
is insanely powerful. Well,
it all comes down
to this. People remember
how you made them
feel more than what
you said. So that
little story you wrote
that creates an emotional
reaction, a feeling, a
memory. And then the
little lesson that follows
that gives them the
logical step. So when
you combine these two
things, it basically makes
people go, oh, that
makes sense. I think
I can do that.
And when they think
like that, they're more
like to action your
advice. And when people
action your free advice
and get a result,
that is the thing
that impacts your business.
And your channel and
creates fans. So the
great thing about these
listicle videos are it's
just intro emotion with
a story logic with
a lesson, emotion, logic,
emotion, logic, like 20
times over making this
the perfect practice ground
for everything else we'll
build on later. Because
the emotion logic framework
is what makes amazing
content. And you're going
to start to spot
it all over the
place on the good
creators now. So now
we're going to turn
your plan into a
good one. So I'm
going to start off
by going into a
script using the emotion
logic structure I've been
showing you. And to
make this easy, I'm
going to show you
two real examples from
my own videos. So
you can see exactly
how this works. So
first up, here's what
one of my lessons
look like as a
plan. So story, I
used to get bullied
by trolls. So I
wasted time fighting them,
but eventually realized it
was a massive waste
of time. And then
the lesson was don't
reply to trolls. So
now what I did
was I fleshed that
out into more of
a script because we
can't just do that
over and over again.
It'll feel a bit
too much. It'll feel
too fast paced for
the viewers. So I'm
going to put the
script on screen and
read it out. See
if you can spot
when I start and
finish the emotion section.
And then when I
hit them with the
logic. And I also
want you to see
how I padded out
this line become a
chunk of a script.
So it's this. Lesson
number five. I was
called a joke for
years in the comments
under my videos. It
really made me want
to defend myself to
show the trolls I
wasn't a joke. So
I'd spend ages crafting
replies. I'd look at
the clock and realize
half an hour had
gone by. Then I'd
post the reply. And
still feel bad. Lesson
number five is to
stop trying to come
up with replies to
hater. You're going to
get a ton of
them. But every second
you waste is a
second you could have
spent on a task
that gets you closer
to your goal. So
that's it, right? So
let's just have a
look at this. So
this in red. That
was the emotion as
it was the story
that hopefully made you
feel something. Possibly because
it felt very relatable.
So you were sitting
there going, that's exactly
how I feel, which
is keeping you hooked.
And then in the
green, that's the logic.
And it's the actionable
lesson that the viewers
can follow. Okay, so
now I'm going to
go one layer deeper
just to show you
what's inside the emotion
brick. So remember early
on I colored my
story so it looked
like this. The red
is the problem. The
orange is the action.
And the green is
the outcome. This is
still exactly the same
in my story in
the emotion brick. You
see that? So like
pause if you want
to have a look.
Then once the outcome
is done, we switch
to logic and just
give the lesson. That's
it. Over and over
again. Problem, action, outcome.
That's the story complete.
Then give the lesson.
Now earlier on in
this video, I said
I was going to
teach you the three
things that are incredibly
powerful and make up
every script. So let's
move on to the
third one now. And
it is this. You
see this little bit
of script where it
says lesson number five.
It's actually a very
important part of the
script and it's known
as a transition. So
one of the jobs
of a transition is
to signal movement so
viewers can understand where
one point ends and
another one doesn't. So
this is where the
transition begins. Now we're
going to go much
deeper on them in
the coming phases. But
for now, this is
all you need to
do to make sure
viewers feel like they're
progressing through what you
promised at the start.
20 lessons. Because without
them, they're going to
feel lost and they're
going to get very
confused and they're going
to go get to
the point because you
don't make it clear
when one's ended and
one's begun. Now that
might sound obvious, but
this is honestly one
of the biggest mistakes
on YouTube. So now
I want you to
do is go and
write every point. So
it's a little bit
more padded out following
that exact same structure
every time. And do
not worry one bit
if it's perfect or
working or might put
your viewers off. We
just got to get
this one done. All
right. So now you've
got your intro, the
body of the script.
Now we need to
end this thing. And
what I want you
to do is I
want you to think
of any video you
already have on your
channel that might be
relevant to your new
positioning. And then what
we're going to do
in our script is
make it sound like
the video they've just
finished watching will not
be effective. If they
don't watch the next
one, which we're going
to point out in
the end screen. So
you're basically saying to
people, although all of
these lessons that I
have just taught you
incredibly powerful. If you
don't know how to
fill in the blank,
then none of them
are going to work.
So watch this video
next where I'll show
you how to solve
that new problem so
that you can get
the result you want.
Now, if you don't
have a video to
pass back to, don't
worry. Just ask them
to subscribe instead. And
do not. Whatever you
do. Don't point them
to a video that
you've not made yet
because you're going to
say, click this video
and it won't be
there. And whatever you
do, don't explain that
it won't be there,
but you'll put it
there another day because
they don't care. They
ain't coming back. All
right. So get that
end screen video now.
And in the next
videos, we're going to
have a little look
at filming and editing.
And then you are
going to post that.
And then after that,
we're going to take
this whole thing that
I've just taught you
next level. We're going
to go next level
on strategy, advanced scripting,
planning, writing, AI measurement.
It's going to be
flipping epic.